So the best way to answer this is to use
最好的方法就是使用 pop
pop. Pop's the only thing we've seen that actually removes
pop 是目前为止我们学过的 唯一一种方法能切实地
elements from a list and it also has the property
从列表中移除元素 并且它还能
that it returns that element. If we do tocrawl.pop() that'll get
返回那个元素 如果我们用 tocrawl.pop()
us the last element in the tocrawl list. Remove that
它将会返回 tocrawl 列表中最后一个元素
element from the list tocrawl. And assign that to the variable
并把这个元素从列表 tocrawl 中移除 之后再把这个元素赋值给变量 page
page. One important point to note is because we're getting
有一点需要注意的是 因为我们先获得的是
the last element first. What we are implementing is what's called
最后一个元素 所以我们这样做被称为
a depth-first search and that means that as we crawl webpages,
深度优先搜索 (depth-first search) 这意味着当我们爬取网页时
If we had three links on the first page. Well, what's
如果我们在第一个页面有三条链接 那么
going to happen is we are going to follow that last link. We're
我们将跟随最后一条链接
going to add the links that we find there to the page.
之后将再把在这里找到所有链接加入页面列表中去
Before getting to these links, well, we're going to follow this link,
在处理这些链接之前 先要跟随这条链接
right? That's going to be the last link that we added. We're
也就是最后添加的这条链接
going to follow that, we're going to get to that page, and we're
跟随这条链接 我们又到达了另一个页面
going to follow the last link on that page. So, this is why
继续跟随页面上最后一条链接 这就是为什么它被称为
it's a depth-first search. We don't get to look at the second
深度优先搜索 我们不会去处理
link on the first page until we've followed all the links that
第一个页面上的第二条链接 直到我们爬取过了
we can reach from the last link on the first page. If
所有能从第一个页面最后一条链接到达的链接
our goal was to get a good corpus of the web quickly,
如果我们的目标是快速得到一个页面的内容
doing a depth-first search would probably not be the best way to
那么进行深度优先搜索 可能并不是最好的方法
do it. And some of the questions at the end of your
你最后的家庭作业中 某些问题
homework, ask you to figure out ways to change the search order,
会让你想出一个改变搜索顺序的方法
that will give us a better way of capturing content on the Web.
这将会给我们一个更好的方法来抓取网页内容
For now, we're going to be happy, and with the
现在 我们可以先高兴一下
test site, it's enough to do a depth-first search. If
因为对于测试网站 深度优先搜索已经足够了
we can complete our search, no matter what order we
如果可以完成搜索 不管是用什么顺序
follow, we'll always find the same set of pages. If
我们都将能找到同样的一组页面
we aren't able to complete the search, and with a
如果我们不能完成所有搜索
real web crawler, there's far too many pages to wait
比如 对于现实的网络爬虫来说 这里有太多页面
until we find them all to return a result, then
我们不能等到它把页面都搜索完 然后再返回结果
the order that we do the pages matters a lot.
这时候 搜索的顺序就会变得非常重要了